Guide to the Benin Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Benin collection
1727-2010
MS 1503
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.27
(6 boxes)
The collection consists of a memoir, speeches, and printed material relating to the history of Benin and the current political and social conditions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of a memoir, speeches, and printed material relating to the history of Benin and the current political and social conditions.
Benin -- Description and travel; Benin -- Politics and government; Benin -- Social conditions
- Original Accession, 1727-1992
  - "Relation de la Guerre de [Juda]": a French naval officer's account of the war between [Juda] and Dahomey, 1727 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political and social organizations: journals, 1978-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Government papers: constitution, speeches, and conference transcripts, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Women's movement: printed material, 1982-1983, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, 1891-1994; Accession 2000-M-009
  - Benin Magazine, no. 9, 1988 January-February (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Centre d'Etude et de Formation pour le Développement (CEFOD), "Une Expérience démocratique: Le Benin depuis la Conférence Nationale Souveraine", 1994 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dahomey [illustrated cards], 1893, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ministère des Finances, "Déclaration du Gouvernement au Sujet du Budget Général de l'Etat Gestion 1994 Amendé par l'Assemblée Nationale", 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Taxi Ville, no. 4, 1991 February-March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Le Petit Journal, Supplementaire Illustré
    - "Amazones, Guerriers et Feticheurs Dahoméens du Jardin d'Acclimation", 1891 February 28 (Folder 2)
    - "Attaque de Dahoméens Repoussée par une Canonnière Française", 1892 August 20 (Folder 2)
    - "Behanzin: Roi du Dahomey", 1892 April 23 (Folder 2)
    - "Le Dahoméen Chedingen: Chef de la Mission du Roi Behanzin à Paris", 1893 November 25 (Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 1956-1995; Accession 2010-M-093
  - Itinéraire dans l'est de l'A.O.F., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The New Benin, a country with a future (Ministry of trade and tourism), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Afrique tu seras libéree!!!, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - République populaire du Benin (communist pamphlet), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le Dahoomey, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1892-2010; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1892-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, Circa 2000 (Folder 2)